

Phone: 415-746-0604 jimmychen.xin@gmail.com

WEBSITE: jimtie.github.io

Hands-on ability to combine user experience studies with programming skills to evaluate system functionality and usability; Proficiency in creating wireframes, storyboards, mockups, and prototypes; Sensitivity to create appealing layouts and visual elements; Solid technical background to facilitate communication with both developers and designers; Good communication skills in teamwork and demonstrating ideas; Passionate and curious about new knowledge. 6+ years professional design experience, been through the full manufacturing process and have learned programming to enhance understanding of production of Apps.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

UI/UX: Axure, Sketch, Marvel POP, Lucidchart, Balsamiq **Visual Processing**: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Digital Drawing: Sketchbook

Front End Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, React, SASS

Back End Programming: Python, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB

Physical Prototyping: Hand Crafting & 3D Printing

CAD modeling: Solidworks, AutoCAD, Rhino, Alias, 3ds-max, Sketchup

Rendering: Keyshot, Vray, Photoview360

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Feb 2020-May 2020 . **FELLOW**

- Expended the understanding of programming languages
- Polished front-end programming skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.is
- Improved the ability of back-end building by using: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Python, PostgreSQL

The main projects I participated:

- Mi-TEA (Personal Concept Project) <u>https://mi-tea.herokuapp.com/</u>
 - o Built a full-stack E-commerce application enable users to purchase tea leaves online
 - Full CRUD, enable user to register, log in,edit personal profiles, save products into cart and checkout: HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, React.js, MongoDB, Express
 - o Strengthened skills in using MERN to create functional E-commerce website
- Infrared (Team Concept Project)

https://github.com/jimtie/Project2

- o Built a full-stack application to share photos and save into customized folders
- Full CRUD, enable user to register, log in, create, edit and delete photos and folders as well: HTML, Materialize, Python, Django, PostgreSQL
- Improved Python/Django coding skills and used PostgreSQL as database
- Toyslist (Team Concept Project)

https://github.com/jimtie/toyslist

- $\circ \quad \text{Built a full-stack application to share used toys or babies' stuff} \\$
- Full CRUD, enable user to register, log in, search, create, edit and delete products: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Express
- Strengthened skills in using JavaScript to build robust, dynamic user interfaces; using Express and MongoDB to build backend
- King Kong Game (Personal Concept Project)

https://github.com/jimtie/Project-0-King-Kong

- o Built a browser based web game, control King Kong to hit the coming planes
- o HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Strengthened skills in object-oriented programming logic and DOM manipulation

Jimmy Chen Résumé, Page 2

QFusion Labs, Inc.
CHIEF INDUSTRIAL DESIGNER / UI&UX DESIGNER

May 2017-Jan 2020. (http://www.qfusionlabs.com)

The product has been sold to 13 states over 50 schools in the US, and used by NASA for teaching and training purposes. (https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/edu/teach/activity/heat-flow-programming-challenge/)

- Created about detailed PRD (Product Requirement Document) for both hardware and software developing.
- Collaborated with clients and creative teams to develop professional and effective packaging for products.
- Conducted brainstorming sessions and designed concepts in line with client's requirements.
- In charge of Manufacturing in China, efficiently schedule time for components purchasing, PCB boards printing, PCB assembly, enclosure injection molding, testing, product assembly, packaging and shipping. Followed up all the process and make sure the process done in a month.
- Worked closely with software engineers to figure out the better solution based on AB testing result
- Worked directly with clients and met them on site to discuss functionalities and design details

Sercle, Inc. CHIEF UI/UX DESIGNER May 2015-Apr 2017 (http://www.sercle.com)

The App successfully got seed funding from Hesong Tang, the previous Vice President of Baidu/ the previous Director of Strategic Investment of Great China Region of Microsoft.

- Designed mobile app UX and UI from scratch.
- Applied knowledge of design software to create eye-catching creative concepts
- Participated in the business execution, used research data to set up business strategy and design as well
- Led the team to update the flow chart, wireframes and graphics
- Created concepts, performance, and production criteria
- Tested product designs using models, prototypes, specialist computer software and computer-aided design

Shook-Design Studio Industrial Designer

Oct 2013 – May 2015 (http://www.shook-design.com)

The main projects I participated:

- -Lotus Elise bumper redesign
- -Smart motorcycle design for Zebra Motors, Denmark
- -Salt Flats Racing car design
- -General Motors Concept car Interior UI design
- -Google campus landscape design
- -Wearable smart device design
- Evaluates design ideas based on factors such as appealing appearance, design-function relationship
- Integrates findings and concepts and sketches design ideas.
- Presents design to clients and discusses need for modification and change.
- Applied knowledge of design software to create eye-catching creative concepts.
- Ensured that designs meet the specific branding requirements and corporate standards.
- Negotiating/agreeing contracts with manufacturers on production of packaging, budgets, time scales and graphics for advertising.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF FINE ARTS, INDUSTRIAL DESIGN, 2014 Academy of Art University, San Francisco, CA, USA

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (INDUSTRIAL DESIGN), 2009 Beijing University of Technology, Beijing, China